And we are live. Welcome on the ship
ship European time edition. Yes, it's a
much better time. Yes, that's going to
be easier to manage for sure and I can
edit the video right away after. Yes,
and we didn't need to drink like three
cups of coffee to just stay awake. That
true true that.
How's the week, man? Oh yeah, okay. So,
before I forget the introduction, I like
the protocol first. Okay.
The the week is good.
We have new models. Yes. Yes, we are
Yes, we Yes, we are.
>> [laughter]
>> That's That yeah, that's good. It's It's
always like good good good exciting when
you don't know if your whole pipeline is
going to crash or not.
It's just like, oh yeah, let's upgrade
and then poof, usage is gone and then,
oh [__] I can't do I can't code
anymore.
Yes, so the first thing we do
just have it retest everything that's
already working to see the quality.
Yeah.
So, yeah, okay. So, I will do the
introduction and then the
we're going to we're going to go with
that. Yes.
It's like Okay, okay.
Last week Anthropic and
OpenAI, yeah, that's a big company,
shipped their own
frontier models
Office 4.7 and Codex 5.5.
The whole timeline is telling you that
the most model that the best model is
the one they're going to use.
We're going to do that, too.
But we're going to compare that and
we're going to even go deeper. So, yeah,
if you want to know how to use those
models,
stay watch this video, subscribe to the
channel, and yeah, that's it.
Enjoy.
Bye.
>> [laughter]
>> I had a different text.
>> Yeah, me too. I
Yeah, because I'm Yeah, forget it. Okay.
We'll chat there. Hey, let me I can't
share. Okay, bye.
Add block list. Thank you for coming.
Bye.
>> Yeah, bye-bye.
So, yeah, um how was your first
impression of first yeah, 4.7 and 5.5,
Mitchell? 4.7 was like all tokens spent
in 10 minutes and the first
>> [laughter]
>> on 5.5 was all tokens spent in 20
minutes. Yeah, that
which But they made an update.
Yes, and since then it works.
Yeah, and
even on 4.6 it's still better.
Yeah, that's that's what I think so.
Like I prefer 4.6. Like right now I'm on
Today I I was using just to explore
Office 4.7 for everything XI.
The usage I had some reserve because
like my yeah, the like over the weekend.
So, until I have the reserve like I'm
going to reach the green light the green
line on
Codex uh
I will
I will slow down after that, but until
now it's good.
I still use it as a orchestrator most
between like Codex and
cloud, but yeah, maybe going to change
based on your feedback, right?
Yeah, well,
>> [laughter]
>> I don't know. So, you are using it for
orchestration of the entire product and
you are having 5.5 doing the coding.
Yes, basically, yes.
I still plan with Office and I I I do I
run the Codex adversarial review Mhm.
and execute with
5.5. And I saw a thread that we're going
to
view together after, but
yeah, you can use 5.5 mini
and it use less token than
yeah, medium and stuff, but even like
less than 5.3
XI, I think.
Oh, that's cool.
>> There was a thread about that. Yeah, I
didn't share it because I saw it like
during the lunch break, but
we're going to review that together
because that could be an interesting way
of using the models. Yeah, but what do
you prefer having the best model doing
the coding or the orchestration?
So,
yeah.
So, what I what now what I'm doing is
like I plan the features. So, now I'm
using Ship Cod more Ship Cod is going to
be my ID soon enough.
Do we have a preview? Yeah. No.
I [laughter]
wanted to show Ship Cod
that, but yeah, you will have the
private review first and then you can
tell me and then we can show it on
stream.
But
yeah, so I have the GitHub issues
on the GitHub project.
Then it's like the PRD style specs, blah
blah blah.
The plan is based on my personal limits
of like which account has the yeah, like
basically the most
capacity to plan and stuff.
And if I'm not limited anymore, but
yeah, usually it's
so Office 4.6
adversarial review Codex
and then
yeah,
I think the default is
Office 4.6 like on effort medium
and then it code and then the reviewer
is Codex.
Because I have the agent that review the
task if it's completely done following
the plan.
Yes, so you have a loop in it. Yes.
So, and right now the loops are failing
all the time when they should not. When
I have a positive output, it failed, so
that's why you don't have it yet.
But yeah, it will be fixed in it.
Yeah.
Yeah,
but yeah, I I don't know. I I get used
to Office. So, it's still planning, it's
still orchestrating, it's still
doing that. So, yeah, did you change?
Because you
I I copy your workflow basically, so
Yeah, I swapped. Yeah.
I'm having
Yeah, I don't know. I'm just keep
swapping because it feels like every
week they have a different way of
working and a different output. Yeah. I
I don't even know
which one to trust properly to just set
as as the default to continue coding all
the time. Yeah, 100% like from one week
to another it's like the whole harness
for on their side on the
like Anthropic servers and
OpenAI servers stuff change.
And it [__] up everything. It's kind
of like annoying.
Yeah, and also the the amount of tokens
you can burn. I was using Codex 5.5 on
my business account, but the business
account is is smaller. You have less
amount of tokens. So, I swapped to the
pro account
and before I was out in like 20 minutes,
my five five-hour limit was reached.
And now I'm at
98% after 4 hours of work.
Yeah, that's
And they said it's only a 10x
difference.
So, I don't get it.
Oh, from enterprise to pro? Yeah. Yeah,
from the business version to pro. They
said if you want to code more, you have
to take pro subscription, but then
it's it's separate from your business
subscription, so I took two.
Okay.
And right now I can just keep on going
with coding. I don't even know. I can
take a look right now. If I just say
start it. See, I've been coding already
for 6 hours today and I still have 95%
left for my five-hour window. On the
five hours, okay. You done like what,
one or two percent on the weekly limit?
Wait, no, it got reset, too.
Oh, that's it. That's
Yeah, it got reset today. Like one
OpenAI guy said,
I don't know
if I should do it, but I want to reset
because we have 5 million users, so How
do we even know what to use?
>> [laughter]
>> I mean, we get more reset on Codex CLI,
though, so Yeah, I don't mind because
I'm still at 99% for the entire week.
Yeah, like maybe I I have the tweet, but
um
Like you you know, he said, oh yeah, I
just used 3%.
Wait.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, yeah, please reset. Exactly.
Well, if this is happening, I don't mind
paying $100 per month. It's cheap. Yeah.
It's uh
Oh, yeah, okay. So,
I've
I'm going to display the
uh your replies.
It's
Yes.
So,
I legitimately believe XI might have a
crazy comeback. Oh, okay. That's That's
That's a do it.
Um okay, where is the reset stuff?
Yeah, please cover this.
Oh, yeah. See,
just yeah.
Don't just reset Codex rate limit for
fun, it costs money. Don't
fun, it costs money.
But the vibes are good. I have reset
Codex rate limit for all paid plans to
celebrate a good week and allow everyone
to build more with ChatGPT 5.5.
So, is it like a marketing stunt or does
every dev have this button on his desk
or maybe he can just press? I I don't
know. Like Okay, so who is this guy? I
think he's
Yeah, Codex. Okay, thank you. Yeah, it
doesn't say what his function is, right?
Notifications.
Uh never talk about governing
Okay. We will ship again this week.
Codex escape velocity and we will keep
improving rapidly. Yeah.
Like I I don't know. I mean, it's good
marketing for sure, right? Because when
you have Anthropic like throttling
everyone
um and and introducing like peak hours
limits
and then you have OpenAI guys just
resetting the limits because it's it's
what it's Tuesday.
I mean, the choice is like
a no-brainer.
Yeah, but
yesterday I read on X that people were
showing a screenshot of
Cloud Code showing on the website that
they are going to take out the Opus
models out of the Pro subscription that
you have to pay additional fees just to
get it.
I want to say it's AB testing, but
I don't think getting this information
on your
on your timeline is good.
Yeah. Ah, for Anthropic that they will
take off Pro?
Yeah. From the 20 bucks
account, right? No, no, no, on the Pro
accounts like the $90 accounts.
Why?
I don't know.
Let me see if I can find it.
Okay.
They can't. That's their like flagship
model.
Yeah, as soon as they take it out, I'm
not paying additional. I'd rather just
pay more at Codex and just have a 20X.
Yeah. Oh, exactly. Yeah, end of growth
Anthropic we're going to cloud removal
from Pro.
Oh, yeah, no, you're right. Small test
on 2% of the new Pro consumer sign-up.
Existing sign-up Max Pro are not
affected. Yeah, yeah, that was not this
one. That was even in another one.
Um
Yeah, but Okay, so I have the Max 20.
Okay, so they will not touch. No, from
Claude
third. Yeah, let me show you the post.
Yes. Yeah, because so you could you
could pay for the Pro and you have
Claude, but
uh
Yeah, I'm I'm already on the Max 20, so
yeah.
And what is it?
Didn't include Claude card. Cowork
didn't exist then. And a journal around
for a while were not a thing. Max was
designed for even chat usage. That's it.
Since then, we brought in Claude card
into Max and it took off after Opus 4.4
uh 4.
Uh Cowork landed long running and
sequential and everyday workflow. The
way people actually use Claude
subscription has changed fundamentally.
Engagement per subscribers is way up. We
made small adjustment along the way.
Weekly caps, title limits as at peak.
But usage has changed a lot and our
current plans were not built for this.
Yeah.
I mean
I think they have a huge compute issue.
Yeah. Because I gave you another DM with
a URL to an X post.
But then you also see people are below
are posting that it is old info from
January. Yeah. Oh, okay.
Oh, like like
uh
Uh we're soon no longer be able to use
Opus model in Claude card. Okay, okay.
The product article shows outdated.
Yeah, okay. Yeah, when I was reading it
yesterday, I couldn't find the info, but
also
it's like as soon as somebody posts
something like this, every big account
is retweeting.
Yeah, I mean, like this one made like
half a million, so I mean, it's it's
it's engagement for a game, right? Like
they will spread this [__] even if
uh
like
uh it's not true, but they're going to
make half a million views out of it.
Yeah.
But on the other hand, we just switched.
The only thing is we don't know what
we're going to get the next week. I I
will I will keep and uh Claude card and
Codex both
for a long time, I think. Yeah. And I'm
still hoping for XAI a just default CLI
integration.
I mean
doing.
I mean, I mean, Meta do you Gemini 3.1?
Yeah. No. Have you ever tried getting a
subscription in Gemini?
I know Claude Code just try finding your
invoices on ChatGPT. Yeah. That's like
Oh, yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> I have like Yeah, like to I have because
I can't think, right? So you need to
download the invoice. Yeah. Bro. And
they say they they email it to you, but
they don't. No. And I wrote down my
email several times, but still I don't
get it.
But even trying to get a Gemini account
that's even worse. Yeah. Yeah, like a
Google console stuff. Like you have
Google console, Google workplace. Well,
yeah.
Yeah, and if you normally don't use
Google
then you just have to search everywhere
and hope you have the correct one and
then try getting a different model, you
have to restart your entire search. Uh
you know why like Google is like so [__]
at like harmonizing their product line?
Yeah, but why? It's because like they
have teams competing with each other
inside the organization.
So like one team will build something
and because they want the man and like
even now the the compute to push
something, they will just ship ship ship
without coordinating about like uh
the whole infra like the whole
infrastructure and the whole
organization to have something like
integrated well.
But then they just say customers will
find it because if they want it, they
will start searching.
Yeah, well, that's the main reason I'm
not using Gemini. I know, exactly.
And Yeah. I think the model is [__]
too.
Yeah, I don't know because I didn't try
it. Yeah.
But I've seen the other people who were
talking on X that Claude Code ruined
their entire business or that they got
blocked by Claude Code.
So they had to swap back to Gemini with
like 60 or 70 devs.
So at least I hope that Gemini can do
the same quality because otherwise
you're [__] if you need to switch.
Yeah. I mean, yeah, for the image that
good, but for the rest
I mean, I I you don't need to try
everything neither, right? Like Claude
Code and Opus are doing the that GPT GPT
5.5 will and Codex
No.
GPT 5.5 plus Opus 4.7 or 4.6
You have a good stack. Yeah, it should
be the just the basic and you can just
let them check each other, so it should
be no problem.
>> Yeah, I know what you're saying.
But yeah, okay. So uh Okay. Uh what
about Yeah, let's check the timeline to
see what they talk about.
Um
like the first feedback of
those models. Because because we can.
Mhm.
Uh so this guy, who is he?
Is the best way to build software with
agents superconductor. Yes, so it's
basically like a personal benchmark.
Uh 5.5 high and even like 5.4 where like
in the top of like average cost per
quality of score like based on their
benchmark. And 4.7 Yeah, it's like far
away.
It's expensive and it doesn't have good
quality, so what the [__] bro? But when
did he do the check? Did he post that as
well?
Uh 24, so 4 days ago. So yeah, last
week.
It could have changed already.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah.
But
I think
like the main point for what I saw from
like other reviewer and feedback and
even like the proper documentation like
the
the way it's built is to be even more
agentic.
Yeah.
Yeah, you have even less and less inputs
to um
It thinks more by itself. Exactly. And
5.5 it required ever better
prompting, I think. I know. Yeah, no, I
think it's 4.7 that required like better
prompting because it's more agentic, so
it
Like basically we use our shitty prompt
for 4.6 to 4.7 and then the quality is
[__] because it almost doesn't work the
same way. Yeah, and then it thinks I
will do it for you. It starts burning
tokens, going searches and you will get
something completely different than you
asked. 20% more expensive than
Yeah, but
if you can use it to do it properly by
having ChatGPT or by Codex 5.5 writing
the prompt in details, then it should be
fine. Exactly. No, no, yeah, yeah, okay.
And that's
Yeah, that's the article I wanted to
share with you because that's exactly
that. Like
if you use Okay, so this one is about
5.5,
but if you use 5.5 on low, you can have
better results
um
than previous models on high and it's
because it will be
faster and can can do more rounds, then
you can also have more iteration.
So yeah, I'm going to drop that.
chat
And if we don't have
a lot of people in the chat, but
uh to you both. Yeah.
Thanks.
But if you need to do
different prompting just to use the
Exactly. model
in the optimal way, then do the
benchmarks even make sense? Because you
the benchmark is the same prompt for
every model. Yeah. I am yeah. But I mean
yeah, you still want to push some um
uh
output on your ways to code for like uh
not GPT but like Opus 5 for example.
Mhm. You can prepare people to even if
you lose the benchmark first.
But you prepare for the next uh
family like the next
the next the next generation.
Then could be worth it, right? But then
yeah, like then ChatGPT 5.5 drops and
then you're losing like 20% of your user
base because they switch to a better
model more adapted to their current
workflow. It's it's a tricky war. Yeah,
yeah. Because if you do the prompt
different, you can get a much better
result. But they don't use it, so they
say it's bad and we're not using it.
Yeah. And exactly. And everyone will
switch and then uh
And then we do the next one. Do you ever
ask a question what could I have
prompted differently and how could I
have differently asked the question to
get a better result?
Uh
not really. I just like fix that [__]
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, okay. Yeah, do you? Yeah, yeah, I
do.
I ask it what could I because sometimes
you just get the first output and it's
really bad. Yeah. And then you're like
working for 30 minutes to get the result
that you want. And that's the moment
when I ask, "Okay, what could I have
asked you in the initial prompt to get
this result directly? And please give me
a few steps."
And I write those down. And when
creating the next prompt, I just put
those steps in.
Okay. So and do you create a skill to
ask better like a prompt engineer skill
stuff or Yeah, I just don't you I don't
install the skills. I just have them,
but you can write them for you for
yourself, right?
>> Yeah, yeah, and I choose which ones to
just include. Yeah.
I mean the skill can be triggered
automatically when you prompt something.
And if you have a prompt skills, then
the skills should check your prompt and
even like re re rewrite the prompt that
the your shitty prompt that you have to
have a prompt that match
the model that you have you are using.
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
So yeah.
That's [laughter]
tricky with AI because bro, like we're
using the same tools. We have different
output.
Yeah, yeah, but we have different ways
of working. Yeah, I mean yeah. I yeah.
Yeah. And it's just minor changes, but
you see what the minor changes do in big
output. Butterfly effect. Like you you
change like you even you prompt like
something a different sentence than from
one word to another and then
Yes. You have a hurricane on the other
side of the world.
Have you tried like
GPT 5.5 design skills? No, not yet.
Yeah.
Like I
I don't I like uh I I have to have my
Claude subscription to edit my front
end. Yeah, well, I'm still arguing with
the front end uh
agents and skills because every time
when I say make this SEO optimized, I
want the best conversion possible. Make
sure that's UX and UI optimized.
I get a result. I see it and I'm like,
"Well, I don't know, but if I don't get
it and I'm the one who who coded it,
then
Yeah.
You can't just write everything down. It
has to be
better. And
did you use like a Claude design?
No, it's all that's the next one. Yeah.
I'm going to test it.
Bro, there's like five five projects a
day that launched and then did you test
it? No. I tested the last week product
already. Like what the [__] Yeah, and
they're already out.
Outdated. Yeah.
But I also like they relaunch the
project. Like everyone forgot about the
project. They relaunch it.
Like for example like [laughter] Google
page.
It's something that launched like 1 year
ago because I had it in my bookmarked.
And then they reannounce it. Oh yeah,
Stitch V2. And they say, "Bro, like
okay, now it's fine." And so they yeah,
they increase the and they make the
announcement like nobody are
nobody else are using it or like know
about the project. They just relaunch
it. Yeah, you're at V2 and then you can
make the cost double.
>> [laughter]
>> And then you just relaunch it.
Like Google relaunch a new project. Oh,
but we added like a year ago. The [__]
Well, if it works, why not?
Yeah.
Uh okay. So this one about ChatGPT.
Okay, so
ChatGPT is definitely the most
interesting and more different model
from OpenAI that we've seen in a long
time.
It should be GPT-6. Yeah, okay,
whatever.
Let's go to the point cost. Is it worth
it? So we know it's about two times more
expensive than GPT-4 per token.
But it use 40% fewer token versus 4.5.
That's why even like you can't even like
trust or
base your own feedback on the cost per
token if the the model is is slashing by
twice the number of token you're going
to use in the next version.
Yeah. Yeah.
What does that mean? Okay, okay. In
artificial artificial
intelligence artificial intelligence
index test, the model used 5.5.4
XI 120 million token, 5.3 XI 77,
and 5.5 XI 75. Yeah?
Yeah, but here they also measure just
the tokens for one prompt, right? Uh I
>> Or just for one project.
I I don't know. Like in the it's the
artificial intelligence index test,
okay? Yeah, well, the the thing is 5.5
is really smart. Yeah.
I I get faster to the results that I
want and I have to correct it less
times. Yeah. Even if it's double in
tokens, I don't mind because it
understands exactly what I want in like
one or two questions instead of six.
Yeah. Yeah, but I see like 5.5 is way
more efficient than 5.4. So
>> Yeah.
They yeah, like there's no point of
staying on 5.5.
But
uh yeah, on Anthropic it's another game.
How does this scale across thinking
level? We can actually be more precise
here. Okay,
5.5 XI high, medium, and low 75 million,
45, 22, and 7.
So you are 10% on low compared to XI.
And what's this guy is explaining like
uh
Okay, this guy.
Um
uh the change picker
extremely efficient. Yeah, 5.5 low is
just not efficient. It's extremely
efficient.
So you can save yeah, token
um
com yeah, compared to the next. Yeah.
Um
Getting is actually yes.
For 5.3 Codex we do not have
public token usage, so we're
extrapolating a little bit of
usage if
5.3 Codex scale the same way, blah blah
blah.
Um okay. So artificial intelligence
index before incorporate 10 evaluation
GDPR. Okay, okay. So it's an aggregate
of multiple indexes.
Um GDP val, bench telecom, terminal
bench, blah blah blah.
Uh cool. And 5.5 XI.
Okay, there is not a
big
difference between XI and
Anthropic. It's a big difference for
them. They charge you more. Yeah.
Yeah,
but no, there is less token use, so the
price per token should be even it's a
more expensive per token, you saved on
the Yeah, you saved on the amount of
tokens.
>> Yes.
So we good.
It's basically the same the same thing,
right?
Uh which means okay, 5.5 is more
intelligent than 5.3 5.3 Codex XI and
use fewer token.
5.5 low is weaker but extremely
efficient. So even for us, you can
plan with Anthropic and use 5.5 low
to execute the plan that you have with
uh
from Anthropic. Yeah, but yeah, from
Codex. But I would still say you can
also just use XI for planning and use
the low for coding. And then use XI
again for checking.
Is that what you do inside the CLI?
Because now you can plan
you can set the effort on planning and
executing, right? Well, before with now
in Codex, I didn't set it up, but before
with Opus when I you was using 4.6,
Yeah. I would use the most smartest
model the highest model on planning.
And I say you are not allowed to code.
You need to spawn agents that code. And
I would use Sonnet to do all the coding.
Okay, yeah. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. So
okay. So you plan and like the when you
execute the plan, the sub agent are
triggered and they use Sonnet. Yeah,
yeah, and they report back to the main
agent that's using the Opus the the high
model. Yeah. And he checks the code that
he gets.
But I'm still using Codex as well, but
he is just checking the plan that was
made by Opus. Mhm.
Yeah, then yeah, okay. So then Ship Code
is useful when you use both and not just
one. Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
Love it. Because
I see that even if I say to Opus I want
to have three different approaches to
tackle this problem,
and all three are still similar. It's
just like it's stuck in the in a certain
way of thinking. But then I use open of
I use Codex and I say I need two
additional
ways to tackle this problem and I get
totally different approaches and I merge
them both into one by saying to Opus,
"Hey, check the other two that were
created by Codex."
And then it says, "Oh, that's a great
idea. I can merge it into my ideas."
Okay, I don't have parallelism.
Okay, I need to
add that.
Let me let me put my into the list.
>> [laughter]
>> Cross-reference problem approaches by
different models.
And that works really good.
It could
uh create two plans from Codex
plus
uh
Opus.
Yeah. And 2 weeks ago
I even I I had to merge all the ideas
into one
uh
plan of how to approach and how to build
it and I made the final question to both
of them to Opus and to Codex.
And my final plan question was
which of the models need to do the
coding and which of the models needs to
do the checking.
And both of them agreed.
Both of them said Opus needs to do the
coding and Codex needs to do the checks
and
and the feedback.
That's crazy.
And I would imagine that Codex would
say, "No, I'm better at coding." And
Opus the same way, but both of them
said, "You need to let Opus do the
coding."
Mhm.
>> [clears throat]
>> Okay. So, I said, "Okay, if you want it,
do it and let me know when it's ready."
Is your workflow like always the same
because like right now what you do is
like copy-paste from one CLI to another,
right?
Yeah, but I also have a Python script
locally that triggers it. Mhm. And I
just puts it in the other one, so that
works as well.
Um and I just let them do the entire
talk in one one document. Mhm. So, I can
read back all the conversation that he
had. Damn.
But every time I do it
in the next week I get different
results. So, my initial start is just a
script like skill that starts up the
entire conversation.
And the further we get, the more manual
input I'm giving because it goes
differently all the time.
Yeah, that sucks. But wait, did you use
that did you use this workflow like
recently or it was like something you
did 6 months ago? No, I've been doing
this like like for two or three months
already every week on different
projects. And you get different results
all the time. Yes. Yeah, that's the
non-deterministic
uh
So, that's why I think it's impossible
to fully automate the entire flow
because you will miss after an update
you won't miss opportunities.
Well, that means like you you have to
force it you have to force the flow.
Like you don't ask the agent, "Oh yeah,
which one should cut?" It's like you you
set up you you opinionated
the workflow and you lock it in like you
put the guardrail. So, you lose that
that maybe the evaluation of the model
or you have one more model that
evaluating always and it only doing
that. Yeah, or you have to make it so
flexible that you have them always
forced
asking the questions and depending on
the result that you get, you choose a
different path. Yeah.
Yeah, you can have a whole llama
connection
Mistral you had to you had you use a
Mistral in the loop.
Yeah.
Do you use which agent you The only
thing I'm thinking about right now that
I never tried
is whatever I ask if they can make an
estimate of the amount of tokens that
they are going to burn building it and
then check how many tokens I have left
in for the next 5 hours
and use that as well to choose which
model is going to build it.
That's pretty cool. So, we can always
keep on going so that we never have to
stop.
Yeah, and then we never release a
a product because uh
Yeah, because we are doing so many
things and we have so many ideas.
On you are always one prompt away from
you like
yeah what you write.
That going to that going to take you
like one month to ship anyway because it
was way harder than just one prompt.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> [laughter]
>> But then when it's done
Yeah. we get a new GPT update.
Uh okay, so GPT
um excite another interesting point. GPT
excite mini cost 1,000 the same test
while low is only 500. At the same time
the artificial blah blah
uh artificial intelligence core
uh for 5.5 low is 51. Wait, okay.
Just uh
benchmark. So,
should you use GPT 5
.5 low for everything? No, of course not
because that would be too easy.
Uh however, just like 5.3 connect the by
thinking model was high. Uh
I mean, all of that like what's the the
point of using low if your limits are
not even hitting anymore?
Yeah, because sometimes it just thinks
too difficult. Yeah.
And what's a diffi- difficult task? Like
changing the color button like like the
No, but that's
instead of just changing the the the
color in the CSS, it just rewrites the
entire button.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, true. Yeah. Yeah, oh yeah, so if
you don't have the thinking in instead
of using your component you have defined
like 6 months ago, it's going to use the
HTML tag and blue.
Yeah. But is there a way to just
automatically switch the model like low,
medium, high
depending on the question that I ask?
Is it Is it doing efficiently? I don't
know. Is it possible to have it analyze
my question, make an
an estimate on what model it needs to do
and then switch the model and perform?
Uh
I don't know. I think it changed the F
like and
I'm not sure, but I think Anthropic has
a auto mode on F4, no?
Yeah, but I don't trust the auto mode. I
think So, then then that's what you were
thinking like you need to build your own
auto
like the F4 router.
Yeah.
Yeah, instead of trusting the Anthropic
that's going to charge you at the end of
the month anyway, right? So, yeah.
Um simple coding smart features low low
low routine development complex system
design. Yeah, okay. Okay, thank you.
Architecture decisions trade-off. Okay.
Okay, cool. Large code base analysis
extremely hard case.
Very hard decision. Okay, so what's a
hard problem? It's a hard problem. Thank
you.
Yeah, but you do that in the planning.
Yeah, also Planning is a hard problem
and you write it down and then
everything is easy because it has an
explanation.
>> Yeah. But I mean the the spawning sub
agents on like on cloud that's
that's good. I think it's yeah. And you
can define that in your settings too,
right? Like uh
The agents only bum. That's it.
Uh okay, it makes sense. Blah blah blah.
Uh
hey, can you still use 5.3 connect? I'm
not going to use 5.3 connect.
No, why should you? Exactly. Um still a
solid option especially if you don't
like a 5.4. In my opinion, this series
should be removed and okay. But yeah, if
if a 5.5 low is good enough to do some
dev, that's definitely interesting.
Yeah, but I would only switch to low
if I run out of tokens on medium.
Yeah. Yeah, or or you can again playing
with Anthropic and then execute on Codex
and then you have infinite
supply of
tokens with
your subscription. Yeah, yeah, a $100 or
$200 subscription is enough for the
entire month. Yeah.
That's cool. Let's go.
So, I never switch to the API. I'm not
paying additional fees. No. I No. Like
I used you know extra usage like for
like last week because I was like yeah I
was out of and then I wanted to try
to do some stuff with Claude.
I have some front-end task.
Bro, one plan three bucks.
Yeah. Just the plan.
>> [laughter]
>> And it was like 11 minutes. Mhm. Three
three dollars.
The what? That's like $20 per hour.
Yeah. I not not not
>> [laughter]
>> So, that's the moment that when we first
said, "Hey, it's cheaper than a a dev in
a in a cheaper country." But right now
>> [laughter]
>> it's not anymore. Yeah, and it's then
the dev is in my country. Yeah, yeah.
Um okay, so I have more tweets about all
of those little stuff. Uh touch.
Uh what was it? Put this into Claude and
the measure your usage in a week. My bet
you will save more than 50% token. Okay,
cool. I yeah because yeah I have a lot
of uh
uh plugin and
and uh yeah prompt to save even more
tokens so we can like excite yeah excite
everything and then
I'm the best project in the world. I
just burn tokens on everything.
But still like a spawn sub agent with a
net context paralyzing different work
offload bugs mechanical task. That's
basically what you're doing.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. For sure.
Uh pick the cheapest model that can do
the subtask well and a cool but
mechanical judgment Sony's cop research.
Code exploration and Opus subtask needed
real planning. So, yeah, with one prompt
you can definitely
I mean, you're good. You could use age.
Good job. Yeah, and sometimes you have
to test. Yeah, and yeah, the
Claude disable one million contacts.
This this feature is useless, bro.
>> [laughter]
>> Why?
I disable it. And something for auto
compact at 80% I do that too and I have
better result too, I think. I just clear
it every time. Yeah, but it yeah, but in
the in the long conversation in the long
thread you compact, you don't wait for
the 100% for auto compact.
>> [clears throat]
>> You do it at
Oh, and he's back.
Oh.
Okay.
Can you hear me? Yeah, yeah, we can hear
you. You went out for a few seconds. No.
But do you trust the auto compact?
It sounds like I don't trust the AI at
all, but I don't know what it's
compacting, so I rather have it write
down where we are right now with a
summary and then just clear everything
and have it read the summary. Yeah, but
sometimes it have to compact in the task
that he's doing too, right?
I I don't let it compact. I just clear
it. Yeah, but like
like the AI is coding Mhm. and it's in
the middle of it
and then it's compacting inside. Oh,
yeah. I think you have better bigger
tasks. Yeah. I think that's the issue.
Oh, yeah.
My bad.
I never have it compacting during during
coding. Okay, yeah, maybe I need to
redefine my my space. Because that makes
me nervous. I don't know what it's doing
and it's in the middle of a task. I
don't know what it's going to forget.
Yeah, that's true. True.
Yeah, that's that's that's true.
Root cause okay, so between March and
April some user on max burn a weekly
quota in one or two days.
Not some user, like everyone.
Yeah. Anthropic chips free bug fixes and
reset our subscription limit blah blah
blah. Yeah, that's the postmortem here.
Nice working like that. Cash misses
context bloat, wrong model or effort,
wrong input format. That's crazy, bro.
Cash misses. Okay, so lock your tools
model at session start. Okay, can't see
anything.
Oop-ah. Yeah, you need hawk eyes to see
this. Like
Uh
Okay, I think
So, lock your tools model at session
start adding a MCP. I don't have any MCP
running except a context seven. I I
Yeah.
I mean
Two years ago MCP were like burning
context. I don't know if they are better
now. I don't have any.
I don't know. The only thing I know is
that my customers that do use a MCP they
are out of tokens so fast. But they just
they also because it's so easy to ask
information
they use it for everything.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
But
I can't have like a
a reset on my weekly subscription on
Monday because I have like five MCP
asking like ask question to
what I'm going to do in the for the rest
of the days, right?
Yeah. Watch the numbers I see 90% of
five minutes before OTT or okay.
So, that was the issue. Context bloat,
Claude keeps re-reading the files. Let's
go.
System prompt clear compact. Yeah, so
compact sub agent and rewind. Yeah?
Did you ever use rewind?
Nope.
Neither. Disable one million
uh
one million context and 80% 200 K
context is plenty. Do that. Just tell
Claude to spawn them everyone in a clean
window. So, that's what you do, right?
With the you with your plan? Yes. Load
lean move rules to skills to
custom
>> [clears throat]
>> custom
custom tools. What the [__]
Reference.md
file progressive disclosure disable
units MCP. Yeah, whatever.
Keep the search reference search don't
ask Claude to grab. Oh.
Okay.
I don't use it.
Compact at 50% or after every task.
Okay.
Rewind after a battle. No, try be keep a
failure in context here for new task.
No, try be keeps the failure in context.
Okay.
I never
>> [snorts]
>> Oh, interesting.
Okay, maybe maybe we should about
rewind.
Uh
Yeah.
Free quality Opus 4.70 for this excite.
[__] off. [__] off.
It'll be there rest to max for demanding
work.
Yeah, but like if you do that uh
Yeah, I did it in my settings. Yeah.
Because it was burning so many tokens.
>> Spell out when to use Opus Sony and
Echo. Okay, swap Anthropic Basil or
open router. What?
Oh, I never did that one.
Swap Anthropic for open router for the
Yeah, but then you what that doesn't
Then you don't make use the cloud
models.
Yeah, but I guess that's not for the
subscription, that's for the API call.
Yeah.
Yeah, okay. A wrong input format agent
browser instead of Chrome MCP.
Full PDF in the report take load to our
PDF text. Okay. Review graph. Yes, I use
those model.
I don't know if they works, but I think
they do and I don't know if you use them
now, but I like them.
Um
Oh, yes, that was the postmortem. Over
the past months of or few reported some
of you
well, your timeline was full.
Claude code quality had slipped. We
investigated and published a postmortem
on the three issue we found.
Yeah, so that's basically what we
Can you make your screen a little bit
smaller so we can read it? Oh, yeah.
Like that. Yes.
Thanks. Yeah, agent SDK honest was also
impacted co-work. Yeah.
Making changes to the time of earlier
including more internal dog fooding.
With config that exactly match those of
our user.
That's because like Anthropic has config
dedicated for them. Mhm. And they just
give us the leftovers. Yeah.
Yeah.
And uh
Codex is doing it differently. That devs
are using the same stuff as we are
using. Yeah.
Yeah. I think that's why they didn't
notice the same issues that we do.
Yeah, I know 100%. And I do you think
like the
um
product quality from OpenAI is better
than Anthropic? It's more stable. Yeah,
it feel it feels better like more
finished and even more polished like the
UI even the front end looks a bit
better, right? Even if Claude Claude is
better than Codex to [__] do the UI,
but that product is all vibe coded by
Claude and it's kind of like eh.
Yeah, that that's how it feels like vibe
coded and we want to be the first one,
just push it. Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, exactly. If nobody complains, then
it's perfect.
>> Yeah, it's not broken. If if you don't
complain, you either don't have user
enough or you
Exactly.
Don't not have not have any enough
usage. Oh, it's good. It's good to go.
Yes, so that was the pricing, but it's
basically the same except
Okay, so GPT-5
output 30
5.5 input five
and output 30 bucks.
4.4 base input five and output token 25.
So, it's basically the same cost.
But okay, there's the
the cash.
Uh
Is there any key for free subscription?
For for what? For
um
You can use open router.
Yeah, open router free?
I
Are you asking us to provide you
a free key?
>> [laughter]
>> It's it's a way to try it. Yeah.
But no, we are paying for our
subscriptions and we don't pay what you
see here for every API call. We use a
subscription, but if you want to do it
free you either need like a big Mac mini
or any other device with a lot of RAM.
So, if you want to spend five to 10 K
for a lot of RAM so you can run a free
model be my guest. Which doesn't work?
Which doesn't work properly and you need
to do so much setup. So,
open router is is the only way to go if
you want to do it free. Like open
router.
Like
uh
like
Oop-la.
Even like here Anthropic. Yes, Claude
Echo.
Okay, Anthropic.
What?
What? Opus
Opus latest.
Okay, and I want the pricing.
I think they add like just two
2% on top of the Yeah, that's not too
much. Yeah. Yeah, I see cash right 56.5
cash read 50 output price 25 what
They don't what? They don't
probably like the pricing model here but
you don't see the the tax.
Cash right 6.5 okay.
So that's fine. Yeah, so it's basically
more or less the same. Did you ever use
like GPT 5.5 Pro?
No. Output 180
I cannot use it with my new subscription
because I switched.
But I didn't do it yet because it was
working perfectly on chat GPT
on Codex 5.5. Yeah.
Yeah, I don't know what
I've no problem either. So yeah, it
works well.
And okay, so some models like modules I
wanted to
talk about before we wrap it up.
So I send you the link directly.
I'm going to read this it's
Yeah, I've done that before.
Yeah.
Wait, coming. Uh
Uh coming.
What the heck?
Okay.
Resize.
So
and
Okay.
Wait, better.
Thank
Nope.
Okay.
Yeah. Uh ATK
it filters and it I think it cache those
commands all of those commands.
Uh
it it cache it on locally so then
Yeah, it helps the LLM to
just have the output of it
directly in cash so it doesn't do it
again. And it's kind
it's straightforward you just install it
like globally and then I didn't need to
do anything it just like all of the
commands are going to ATK
after so yeah, I recommend this one.
Um Caveman
if you want code code to just talk to
you like straight to the point.
That'll be good. Give me code. Exactly.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh and also it's kind of smart because
when the error is too complicated and
you need to more explanation it disable
Caveman
explain to you clearly Mhm. and then you
can go back to Caveman mode.
Oh, that's cool. Yeah, it's it's it's
really good.
Uh so there is that and yeah, code
review graph it's another
uh plugin
yeah, plugin that helps you cash
everything and I use it it will I think
it works great.
Um so yeah, that's the three one that I
use to reduce my token usage. So yeah,
also I can really
uh tell if like the cost is less than
last week because of that or because of
chat GPT usage but at least I have still
have my
my weekly limit.
Uh for the last
two days so I'm good.
Okay, cool. Yeah.
But yeah, other than that
I think oh yeah, open router models
all the all the small models like going
to be a ranks ranking.
Yeah, but who uses all those models?
I mean
uh
Kimmy 2.6 it's like it's a good one
compared to the
um the others and yeah, like if you use
it for the open router that I can see
Like if you hit your limit on Claude you
can use Kimmy 2.6. Yeah, yeah, that's
true.
Uh deep seek Gemini flash okay.
Uh Grok yeah, good luck with that and
office 4.6
oh 4.6 okay.
Yeah, 1.1 token but yeah, it's kind of
crazy because okay, it's the token usage
but if you are efficient enough
uh then you use less tokens so yeah.
Yeah, it's about optimizing your own
workflow. Exactly.
Uh okay, so there is that that that's we
talk about that we talk about that.
We saw that too.
Uh GPT 5.5 is 34% cheaper than office
uh 4.7 right? What? I thought it was
I think this is this shows that it
depends on how do you use it what
prompts do you give it
etc. etc. etc. and that all gives you a
different result each time. It's it's
not.
And then people put it in a chart and
they just post it and everybody's happy.
Yeah, 100k views let's go.
Yeah. Yeah, and yeah, what cash cash
drive free oh yeah, because I think
yeah, also take that so when you loop
and then yeah, okay and anthropic charge
for cash right in addition to cash read
open AI only charge for cash read so
then if you have more if you go to the
cash more often
uh then it's completely different. And
then I saw one guys saying that if you
cash the sessions
then it's going to be like crazier.
Uh yeah, I see like 5.5 is still very
slow and keeps making silly mistakes.
You don't have that experience.
No, I don't and I'm on medium. Yeah.
Yeah, it's
Uh others comparing exciting yeah, okay,
whatever uh will be curious so much on
the on effects thinking budget has Yeah,
it's it's so hard to compare all of
those. But also he says it makes it
silly mistakes. How good is his input?
Yeah, exactly. Yeah, they're like the
bug can be between the chair and the
computer right? Yeah, he can say I have
a bug it doesn't work and enter and
that's it. Yeah, I mean front end if
it's a front end task I will not still
not giving it to Codex anyway so
Yeah.
But
okay, I think
we are Yeah, we still need conclusion
right? Which model is better?
So
uh yeah, you want to conclude? I want to
conclude.
Go for it. It doesn't matter which model
you use you just have to give the proper
input. Yeah, I use both. Use both having
correct each other. Yeah.
Like through orchestration.
And if you don't know how to do it ask
us. Yeah. We are your debugging. I like
those videos like after 1 hour
conclusion is
Ask us we know what to do and otherwise
we will make sure that we find out. 500
500 dollars an hour ask us thank you.
Yeah, you get both of us.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah, but yeah, okay, so I think that's
it. We can wrap it up right?
Mitchell thank you so much for your time
and yeah, those European hours are late.
It was much better.
>> [laughter]
>> So let's go. Thank you so much. We will
see you all next week. Subscribe to the
channel. Uh like share with your dev
friends and non-dev friends because we
need people on the channel so chop chop.
And yeah, see you next week. Bye and a
video later this week. Bye.
Bye-bye.